JACOB KIM JOHNSON

(608) 790-7675 | jacob.kim.johnson@gmail.com | jacobkimjohnson.com | Irvine, CA

PROFILE

I'm a UX/UI designer and visual designer with over six years of experience in industries including startups, tech, and nonprofits, which has given me a unique ability to examine situations and consider strategies from different perspectives. Having a passion to understand users as holistically as possible, I use thorough research and analysis to help me create elegant and engaging experiences. Additionally, my empathy, critical thinking, and collaborative nature have contributed to my understanding of user behaviors and motivations, as well as have encouraged me to make thoughtful decisions.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

UX/UI DESIGNER, TIM / MEDIA SERVICES

Los Angeles, CA | Jan. 2019-Present

- As the senior designer, conceived user interface concepts to create and improve experiences on a SaaS application platform
- Using Agile methodology, collaborated with project managers, engineers, and stakeholders to simplify and solve complex problems throughout the application
- Created wireframes and interactive prototypes of designs to effectively communicate concepts for the entire team to understand
- Collaborated with client support team and met with clients to help identify and understand pain points within the application
- Developed brand and design guidelines to ensure consistency and integrity within the application
- Designed and created visual elements within the application to improve the visual integrity

UX/UI DESIGNER, VISUAL DESIGNER, & WEB DEVELOPER, SELF-EMPLOYED

Los Angeles, CA | Aug. 2017-Present

- Crafted user experiences by designing and developing user-centric, mobile-first web apps from scratch (using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript)
- Created UX deliverables including wireframes, prototypes, and user flows
- Consulted with organizations on how to improve overall user experience
- Collaborated with web developers to provide designs that are in line with current and effective web practices
- Refined typography execution with font pairings, hierarchy, and spacing
- Refined aspects of visual design, like color theory and visual hierarchy/spacing
- Designed and created graphics for logos and web content
- Researched ongoing design trends, both in UX/UI and visual composition

UX/UI DESIGNER, GRAPHIC DESIGNER, & WEB CONTENT COORDINATOR, CBE INTERNATIONAL

Minneapolis, MN | Jul. 2014-Sept. 2017

- Helped plan, research, test, and implement website functionality and design to improve user experience for conversion-oriented interface
- Informed by user research and web analytics, led initiatives which helped increase annual web traffic by over 110%
- Improved social media strategies to be more visual, better suit reader interest, and increase interaction
- Created wireframes and mockups of web pages to communicate updates and redesigns with the team
- Created UX user personas and conceptualized journey maps to better understand goals for the users
- Operated under an Agile-like iterative and continuous design process, and met developers on a daily-to-weekly basis to work through design specifications
- Created and designed both digital and printed materials, including ad images, logo concepts, and book layouts
- Edited and managed web content with Drupal CMS and HTML/CSS

MARKETING SPECIALIST (CONTRACTOR), CATS SOFTWARE, INC.

Minneapolis, MN | Apr. 2014-Jul. 2014

- Researched user experience and competitors to help encourage strategies to improve the application
- Experienced Agile methodology with daily standup meetings and JIRA for project management to establish company synergy
- Created icons, graphics, and cartoons as companions to blog articles and social media posts
- Wrote blog posts and managed social media accounts to help facilitate conversation among users for start-up organization

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF ARTS (BUSINESS MANAGEMENT, PSYCHOLOGY)

Luther College, Decorah, IA

CERTIFICATE (WEB DESIGN & GRAPHIC DESIGN)

Minneapolis Community & Technical College, Minneapolis, MN

SKILLED WITH

- Sketch
- Figma
- Invision
- Adobe CC
- Zeplin